Guide to the Herbert Lough Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Herbert Lough papers
1900-1951
1910-1914
SC0281
Lough, Herbert.
3 Linear feet
Exams and notes from various courses, mostly in economics and history. Additional school papers from Lough's work at North Division High School in Chicago ca. 1906-10. Also newspapers relating to Stanford athletics 1913-51 and a special PALO ALTO TIMES series commemorating Stanford's 50th anniversary. Miscellaneous items related to Stanford student activities 1910-14 and the Pacific Southwest Tennis Tournaments of 1933 and 1937.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Lyman Lough, 1982.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Herbert Melville Lough was a student at Stanford from September, 1910, until May, 1914, when he graduated with an A.B. in economics.
Description of the Collection
Exams and notes from various courses, mostly in economics and history. Additional school papers from Lough's work at North Division High School in Chicago ca. 1906-10. Also newspapers relating to Stanford athletics 1913-51 and a special PALO ALTO TIMES series commemorating Stanford's 50th anniversary. Miscellaneous items related to Stanford student activities 1910-14 and the Pacific Southwest Tennis Tournaments of 1933 and 1937.
Access Terms
Lough, Herbert.; North Division High School, Chicago (Ill.).; North Division High School,. (Location of Meeting--Chicago, Ill.; ); Pacific Southwest Tennis Tournament, Los Angeles (Calif.).; Pacific Southwest Tennis Tournament. (Location of Meeting--(Los Angeles, Calif.); ); Stanford University -- General subdivision--Students.;; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Stanford University. Department of Economics.; Stanford University. Department of History.
Collection Contents
- STANFORD COURSES
  - Algebra III - Exams, notes (1911) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bionomics 11: Evolution - Exams (1912) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Economics 1 - Exams (1911-12) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Economics 4: Money & Banking - Exams, notes (1912-13) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Economics 5: Transportation - Exam (1913) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Economics 8: Corporations - Exams, notes (1912-13) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Economics 11: Public Finance - Exams (1913-14) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Economics 12 - Notes (1913-14) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Economics 14: Corrections - Exam (1914) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Economics 16: Market Organization - Exams, notes (1912) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Economics 24: [Secretary Training?] - Exercises (1914) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Economics 30: Comparative Federal Government - Exams (1912) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Economics 32: Municipal Government - Exams, notes (1912) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Economics 33: Parliamentary Government - Exams (1913) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Education 2: Educational Theory (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - English 1 and 1a - Notes and misc. (1911?) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - English 2 and 3 (ca. 1910 - 1913) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - English 2 and 3 (ca. 1910 - 1913) (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - English 5: English Classics - Notes, exams (1910-11) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - French 1a: Elementary French - Exams, exercise books (1910-11) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - French 3: Modern French Reading - Exams (1911) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - History 3a & 3b: Middle Ages - Exams, notes (1910-11) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - History 3a & 3b: Middle Ages - Notes (1910-11) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - History 3a & 3b: Middle Ages - Notes (1910-11) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History 3a & 3b: Middle Ages - Notes (1910-11) (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - History 3a & 3b: Middle Ages - Notes (1910-11) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - History 5b - Exam (1912) (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - History 7a & 7b: U.S. History - Exams, notes (1911-13) (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - History 9b: The Far East - Exam (1914) (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Philosophy 3: History of Philosophy - Exam, notes (1913) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Philosophy 8: History and Application of Theory of Evolution - Exam (1913) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Physiology 1: Exams, notes (1910-11) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Psychology 1 & 1a: Exams, notes (1911-12) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notebooks: Economics 16, 30; Organic Evolution (1912) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notebooks: Economics 5, 35 (1913) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Notebooks: Philosophy 8; Education 2; History 7; Accounting (1913) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Notebooks: Economics 14; History 9 (1914) (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Notebooks: Philosophy 3; Economics 11 (1913-14) (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Notebooks: Miscellaneous (secretary training, labor seminar, temporaneous speaking, hygiene, foreign exchange, statistics, financial history, taxation, tariffs) (1914) (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous notes on history, economics, philosophy (Box 3, Folder 11)
- PRE-STANFORD SCHOOL PAPERS
  - Composition book - Misc. notes and address lists (1900-06) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Biology (ca. 1909) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Physiography, chemistry notes (1906-10) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Ivanhoe Historical Notebook Series, Part V: to accompany English History (ca. 1910) (Box 4, Folder 4)
- MISCELLANEOUS ITEMS
  - Senior Class Play, 1910: "As You Like It" - Program (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Senior Week, May 1914 - Invitation and program (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - L.A. Tennis Club - Tournament programs (1933, 1937) (Box 4, Folder 7)
- NEWSPAPERS (GROUPED BY SUBJECT)
  - Stanford 50th Anniversary - Palo Alto Times series (1941) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Stanford basketball (1938) (Box 5 os, Folder 2)
  - Stanford track (1914-34) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Stanford football (1914-51) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stanford rugby (1913-14) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Misc. Stanford (ca. 1914-41) -- including Lamson trial (1935); retirement of Coach Harry Maloney (1941); Stanford Axe (1930); arrival of freshmen (ca. 1914) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Misc. non-Stanford (1913-41) (Box 5, Folder 7)